Finding aid for the Gene Roddenberry Star Trek Television Series Collection PASC.0062
UCLA Library Special Collections
- CORRESPONDENCE/GENERAL FILES
  - PUBLICATION TIE-INS
    - Correspondence regarding Publications linked to Star Trek. Includes correspondence regarding Mack Reynold's novel and James Blish's adaptation of the TV series. Total Items: 31 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence regarding articles, interviews, press luncheons, promotional material. Total Items: 104 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence regarding articles, appearances, fan mail, promotional materials. Also includes photos sent by Jet Propulsion Laboratories. Total Items: 102 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence regarding newspaper articles, appearances, & the Save Star Trek Campaign. Total items: 96 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - RATINGS
    - Lists of ratings results, and poll results for TV Week. Total Items: 39 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - REJECTED WRITERS
    - Letters to writers rejecting their story outlines. Total Items: 38 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - RE-RUNS
    - Correspondence regarding re-runs, including Re-run lists, schedules, and quantities of re-runs necessary. Total Items: 11 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - ROARKE, ADAM
    - List of credits, contract. Total items: 3 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - SALES
    - Correspondence to and from Desilu Sales, regarding opals & foreign sales. Total Items: 5 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - SCIENCE FICTION ORGANIZATIONS
    - Correspondence regarding science fiction organizations & conventions, including the Science Fiction Writers of America, the 24th & 25th World Science Fiction Conventions, Westercon XX, and the Count Dracula Society. Total Items: 99 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence and copies of science fiction publications, including Yandro. Also includes fanzines published for Save Star Trek Campaign. Total Items: 64 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - SCREENINGS
    - Correspondence regarding the scheduling of screenings and their attendance. Total Items: 16 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - SETS
    - Correspondence regarding set cost, decoration and storage. Console component list, booklet on using spray foam for set construction. Total Items: 33 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Jefferies, Matt (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - SHATNER, WILLIAM
    - Correspondence concerning William Shatner, specifically compensation and agreements, his weight, insurance, and invitations. Total Items: 55 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - SOHL, JERRY
    - Correspondence between Jerry Sohl & Roddenberry, and letters from Sohl to Damon Knight. Total Items: 16 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - SOUND, EDITING & MIXING
    - Correspondence regarding sound editing and mixing, specifically: dubbing schedules, staff and salary recommendations, congratulatory letters, comments on editing sound to picture. Total Items: 19 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - SPECIAL EFFECTS
    - Correspondence, including optical effects costs, miscellaneous effects, effects budget, & a subliminal montage list. Total Items: 72 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - SPINRAD, NORMAN
    - Correspondence to, from, and regarding Norman Spinrad, including compensation, story outline, discussion of story outline and SF in film. Total Items: 6 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - STOCK FOOTAGE
    - Correspondence regarding available stock footage, and Star Trek's stock footage library. Total items: 26 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - STORY SUMMARIES
    - Summaries of science fiction short stories and their themes. Total Items: 107 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Stories and correspondence critiquing stories, also general correspondence referring to stories (G. Roddenberry, B. Justman, H. Solow, D.C. Fontana, G. Coon). Total Items: 100+ Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Roddenberry, Gene * Justman, Robert * Coon, Herb * Fontana, D.C. * Solow, Herb (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - TAKEI, GEORGE
    - Correspondence regarding public appearances, role of Sulu, agreements and compensation, letter from Takei to Roddenberry. Also includes contract. Total Items: 14 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - TECHNICAL RESEARCH, MISCELLANEOUS MATERIALS
    - Magazines, reports and photos used as technical research for Star Trek. Includes Reports from NASA, Dynatherm & Harvey Lynn, reports on Lunar vehicles, basic astronomy. Rocketdyne photos, copy of the National review & Westways. Total Items: 71 (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Newspaper clippings of articles on science issues and news used for research. Total Items: 85 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - THEISS, BILL
    - Thank you letter, letter discussing contest. Total Items: 2 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - TOY DEVELOPMENT CENTER
    - Correspondence regarding Reuben Klmaer of Toy Development Center, agreements to create Phaser Rifle, and other merchandise. Total Items: 5 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - WARDROBE
    - Photos of man wearing various uniforms, negative strips of photos. Total Items: 34 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence regarding costumes, emblems, costs, & SF convention fashion show. Also includes sketch of uniform. Total Items: 18 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Theiss, Bill (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - WERNER, MORT
    - Correspondence between Werner and Roddenberry, social correspondence. Total Items: 5 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - WESTHEIMER COMPANY
    - Correspondence to and regarding the Westheimer Company, specifically optical effects & a thank you note. Total Items: 2 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - WHITFIELD, STEVE
    - Part I of (typed) manuscript THE MAKING OF STAR TREK by Steve Whitfield, n.d., w/annotations. Sent to Roddenberry for comment/edit. Also includes Star Trek presentation and pilot story outline of "The Cage". Total Items: 176 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Part 2 of (typed) manuscript THE MAKING OF STAR TREK by Steve Whitfield, n.d. Sent to Roddenberry for comment/edit. Total Items: 134 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Part 3 of (typed) manuscript THE MAKING OF STAR TREK by Steve Whitfield, n.d., w/annotations. Sent to Roddenberry for comment/edit. Total Items: 113 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Partial manuscript THE MAKING OF STAR TREK by Steve Whitfield, n.d. Sent to Roddenberry for comment/edit. Total Items: 63 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Summary of proposed Star Trek book by Steve Whitfield and Gene roddenberry. Chapter-by-chapter outline. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Roddenberry, Gene (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - WHITNEY, GRACE LEE
    - Correspondence regarding contractual obligations, the Yeoman role, and names for Yeoman. Also includes photo of Grace Lee Whitney. Total Items: 8 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - WILD LINES
    - Lists of wild lines to record. Total items: 9 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - WRITERS, GENERAL
    - Writers' resumes, correspondence to and from writers, correspondence regarding writers strike, and lists of writers. Total items: 100+ (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Rough drafts & 1 final draft of writer-director information, briefly explaining the Star Trek universe and laying out guidelines for writers. Total Items: 100+ (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence to and from Writers Guild, including a newsletter from the Writers Guild and an award notification. Total Items: 5 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Writers Report sheets listing story #, writer, episode title, and status of script. Total Items: 50 (Box 35, Folder 15)
- UNPRODUCED MATERIALS
  - ALADDIN'S ASTEROID
    - 1) Step Outline by Robert Barry, 5/22/67 (27). Total Items: 27 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Barry, Robert (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - THE AURORALS
    - Materials: 1) Story Outline by Frank Paris, 6/13/68 (12) 2) Story Outline, 6/20/68 (14) 3) Correspondence: National Broadcasting Company, 6/26/68 - 6/27/68 (2). Total Items: 28 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Paris, Frank * Robertson, Stanley * Messerschmidt, Jean (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - THE BEAST
    - Materials: 1) Story Outline by Marc Daniels, 7/1/68 (9). Total Items: 9 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Daniels, Marc (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - BEM
    - Materials: 1) Story Outline + BEM sketches by David Gerrold, 3/14/68 (27) 2) Revised Outline, 4/4/68 (23) 3) BEM Sketches, 3/14/68 (7) 4) Correspondence: Desilu Productions, 3/12/67 - 4/17/68 (4). Total Items: 61 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Gerrold, David * Roddenberry, Gene (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - BEWARE OF GRYPTONS BEARING GIFTS
    - Materials: 1) Story Outline by David P. Harmon, 4/16/68 (7) 2) Correspondence: Desilu Productions, 4/17/68 - 4/29/68 (3). Total Items: 10 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Harmon, David * Roddenberry, Gene * Justman, Robert (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - DESTINATION: INFINITY
    - 1) Story Outline by Robert Barry, 3/30/67 (17) 2) Correspondence: Desilu Productions (3). Total Items: 20 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Barry, Robert * Justman, Robert * Fontana, D.C. * Roddenberry, Gene * Coon, Gene (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - FOR THEY SHALL INHERIT
    - 1) Story Outline by Jerome Bixby (13). Total Items: 13 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Bixby, Jerome (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - THE FORBIDDEN
    - 1) Story Outline by Hank Stine (12). Total Items: 12 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Stine, Hank (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - THE FORCES
    - 1) Story Outline by Charles Parker (10, 2 copies). Total Items: 20 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Parker, Charles (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - THE FORSEEABLE FUTURE
    - 1) Story Outline by Jean Lisette Aroeste, 8/22/68 (14) 2) Story Outline, 9/16/68 (10). Total Items: 24 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Aroeste, Jean Lisette (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - FROM THE FIRST DAY TO THE LAST
    - Untitled draft, n.d., 34 pgs. (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - A FUZZY THING HAPPENED TO ME
    - Correspondence re the script, June 1967. Total item: 7 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - THE GODHEAD
    - Materials: 1) Story Outline by Lucas, 3/15/68 (20) 2) Revised Outline by Lucas, 4/17/68 (15) 3) Outline by Lucas, 11/7/68 (15) 4) Correspondence: Desilu Productions, National Broadcasting Company, 3/15/68 - 11/14/68 (4). Total Items: 54 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Lucas, John Meredyth * Roddenberry, Gene * Justman, Robert * Robertson, Stanley (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - HE WALKED AMONG US
    - 1) Story Outline by Norman Spinrad, 5/12/67 (13) 2) Story Outline, 5/17/67 (16) 3) Story Outline, 5/18/67 (16, 2 copies, 1 w/annot.) 4) Teleplay, 9/28/67 (69) 5) Correspondence: Desilu Productions, NBC, 5/15/67 - 10/2/67 (77). Total Items: 207 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Spinrad, Norman * Fontana, D.C. * Justman, Robert * Coon, Gene * Messerschmidt, Jean * Roddenberry, Gene (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - IMAGE OF THE BEAST
    - 1) Story Outline by Philip Jose Farmer, 3/27/66, (3). Total Items: 3 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Farmer, Philip Jose (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - IN ESSENCE - NOTHING
    - First draft script by Judy Burns and Chet richards, May 31, 1968. 68 pages. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Burns, Judy * Richards, Chet (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - JOURNEY TO REOLITE
    - Materials: 1) Story Outline by Alfred Brenner, 4/18/66 (24) 2) Script Materials: Notes on Story Outline (1) 3) Correspondence: Desilu Productions 4/18/66 - 4/20/66 (2). Total Items: 27 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Brenner, Alfred * Justman, Robert * Black, John D.F. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - THE JOY MACHINE (AKA THE ROOT OF EVIL)
    - 1) Story Outline by Theodore Sturgeon, 5/16/67 (20) 2) Story Outline by Theodore Sturgeon, 6/23/67 (15) 3) First Draft Teleplay by Meyer Dolinsky, 10/21/68 (61) 4) Correspondence: 5/23, 6/15,11/15 1967 (4). Total Items: 100. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Sturgeon, Theodore * Dolinsky, Meyer * Roddenberry, Gene (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - MACHINES ARE BETTER
    - Materials: 1) Story Outline by A.E. Van Vogt 3/29/67 (20) 2) Correspondence: Desilu Productions, National Broadcasting Company 3/30/67 - 5/8/67 (14) 3) Financial: Contract Request Form (1). Total Items: 35 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Van Vogt, A.E. * Justman, Robert * Roddenberry, Gene * Fontana, D.C. * Robertson, Stanley * Perlstein, Ed (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - MERE SHADOWS
    - 1) Story Outline by Philip Jose Farmer, 3/26/66 (12). Total Items: 12 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Farmer, Philip Jose (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - MOTHER TIGER
    - 1) Correspondence: Desilu Productions (11). Total Items: 11 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Bixby, Jerome * Roddenberry, Gene * Klement, Otto (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - THE ORCHARD PEOPLE
    - Story outline by Catherine Turney and John Collier, 7 pages. Memos(3), 3 April, 1967. Total items: 10 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Turney, Catherine * Collier, John (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - PANDORA'S BOX
    - 1) Correspondence: Desilu Productions, 8/29/67 - 9/14/67, (13). Total Items: 13 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Aubry, Daniel * Fontana, D.C. * Justman, Robert (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - RETURN TO EDEN
    - Materials: 1) Story Outline by Boretz, 5/9/66 (13) 2) Revised Outline, 5/23/66 (18) 3) Correspondence: Desilu Productions, 4/22/66 - 5/26/66 (16). Total Items: 47 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Boretz, Alvin * Black, John D.F. * Justman, Robert * Roddenberry, Gene (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - RITES OF FERTILITY
    - Materials: 1) Story Outline by Robert Sheckley, 5/6/66 (23) 2) Correspondence: Desilu Productions, 5/6/66 - 5/11/66 (4). Total Items: 27 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Sheckley, Robert * Justman, Robert (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - ROCK-A-BYE-BABY, OR DIE
    - Materials: 1) Outline by George Clayton Johnson, 8/2/66 (12) 2) Correspondence: Desilu Productions, 8/8/66 (1). Total Items: 13 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Johnson, George Clayton * Justman, Robert (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - THE SEARCH FOR ETERNITY
    - Materials: 1) Story Outline by A.E. Van Vogt, 4/11/67 (9), Correspondence April 12/13, 1967. (3). Total Items: 12 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Van Vogt, A.E. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - SHOL
    - 1) Story Outline by Darlene Hartman, 7/15/67 (15), 2) Story Outline, 7/24/67 (17), 3) First draft teleplay, 8/23/67 (62), 4) Correspondence: Desilu Productions, National Broadcasting Company, 3/23/67 - 10/16/67, (81). Total Items: 158 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Hartman, Darlene * Fontana, D.C. * Justman, Robert * Roddenberry, Gene * Robertson, Stanley * Coon, Gene (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - SHORE LEAVE II
    - Materials: 1) Story Outline by Theodore Sturgeon, 4/24/68, (33) 2) Correspondence: 4/29/68 (1). Total Items: 34 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Sturgeon, Theodore * Justman, Robert (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - SISTER IN SPACE
    - Materials: 1) Story Outline by Robert Sheckley, 6/14/66 (8) 2) Correspondence: Desilu Productions, 6/12/66 - 6/15/66 (2). Total Items: 10 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Sheckley, Robert * Black, John D.F. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - SKAL
    - Materials: 1) Story Outline by Jerome Bixby, n.d. (21). Total Items: 21 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Bixby, Jerome (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - SLEEPING BEAUTY
    - 1) Story Outline by Robert Bloch (7). Total Items: 7 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Bloch, Robert (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - THE SQUAW
    - Materials: 1) Step Outline by Shimon Wincelberg, 7/15/66 (14) 2) Revised outline, 7/28/66 (11). Total Items: 25 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Wincelberg, Shimon (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - THE SURRENDER OF PLANET X
    - 1) Story Outline by Don Masselink, n.d. (4). Total Items: 4 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Masselink, Don (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - THE UNCOILER
    - 1) Story Outline by Philip Jose Farmer, 4/1/66 (13) 2) Revised Story Outline by Philip Jose Farmer, 4/5/66 (25), Note April 22, 1966 (1). Total Items: 39 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Farmer, Philip Jose (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - UNTITLED
    - Materials: 1) Story Outline by Robert Sheckley, n.d. (4). Total Items: 4 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Sheckley, Robert (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - 1) Story Outline by Jerome Bixby, n.d. (9, 2 copies). Total Items: 18 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Bixby, Jerome (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - THE V.I.P.S
    - 1) Story Outline by Gene Lesser and Malachi Throne (5). Total Items: 5 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Lesser, Gene * Throne, Malachi (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - WARRIOR'S WORLD
    - 1) Story Outline by S. Kandel, 4/22/65 (14) 2) Story Outline, 4/28/65 (19) 3) Story Outline, 4/28/65, (19, 2 copies, 1 w/annot.) 4) Story Outline, 5/7/65 (21) 5) Correspondence: Desilu Productions, 4/26/65 (8) 6) Notes, handwritten. Total Items: 8 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Kandel, Stephen * Roddenberry, Gene (Box 26, Folder 2)